Charles R. Martin Photographs, 1945-2011 AIS.2012.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Charles R. Martin Photographs
1945-2011
1966-1999
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Martin, Charles R.
AIS.2012.04
17.25 Linear Feet (143,000 35mm negatives; 1,000 4x5 negatives; 1,096 120 mm negatives; assorted gelatin silver prints)
The collection documents Charles R. Martin's 66-year career as a private photographer, with images dating from the 1940s to 2011. The collection contains images taken during his work with clients such as the United Way of Allegheny County, Dynamic Equipment, St. Barnabas Foundation of Gibsonia, the Boy Scouts of America, Carlow College, Vibra Tech Engineers, Alcoa and Red Valve, among others. Also included in the collection are personal and travel photographs. Of particular note is a series of 189 photographs taken on Sunday, April 7, 1968, three days after the assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., which depict a peaceful march in Pittsburgh on the National Day of Mourning in memory of Dr. King. Digital reproductions of these photographs are online.
Previous Citation
Charles R. Martin Photographs, 1945-2011, AIS.2012.04, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Biography
Charles (Chuck) R. Martin was born to a lawyer and classical singer in Beaver Falls, Pa., on July 1, 1927. He credited his uncle, an amateur photographer, for sparking both his love of photography and his future career. After graduating from Beaver Falls High School in June of 1945, he joined the Navy where he served 14 months on the Lyman K. Swenson destroyer. It was during this time that he purchased his first camera, a Leica II, for $100 in Shanghai, China.
After his military service, Martin attended Dartmouth College where he majored in art and zoology, thinking that he would go into medical photography. As a student at Dartmouth, he served as president of the photography club and had some of his photographs published in the Dartmouth College Weekly Calendar. Martin returned to Beaver Falls after graduation where he met Sally while she was still a student at Geneva College. They married in 1950 and had three children: Catherine (Kitty), William (Mac) and Tom.
It was not until his wife took a teaching job, years later, that Martin was able to get into free-lance photography after working in a variety of jobs from car salesman to owning his own real estate company. He soon built up an impressive clientele, including the United Way of Allegheny County, Dynamic Equipment, St. Barnabas Foundation of Gibsonia, the Boy Scouts of America, Carlow College, Vibra Tech Engineers, Alcoa, and Red Valve. Martin said his goal was always to try to capture, what the French photographer Henri Cartier-Bresson termed, "the decisive moment."
Martin had a strong artistic side to his photography. By showing a slide show he created using his nature photography along with Aaron Copeland's "Appalachian Spring" to a friend with connections to the Butler symphony; Martin began what would become a 30-year relationship with the symphony. This lead to other programs designed around notable pieces such as "Mysterious Mountains," "The Pines of Rome," and "The Grand Canyon Suite," among others.
Martin passed away on July 8, 2013.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by Charles Martin in November 2012.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into three series by format and chronologically by year. Arrangement follows the original numbers assigned by the photographer.
Series I. Pittsburgh March on the MLK Jr. National Day of Mourning, April 7, 1968
Series II. Negatives, 1945-1998
Series III. Prints, 1950-2011
Scope and Content Notes
The Charles R. Martin Photographs is comprised of photographic prints, negatives and a small amount of manuscript material that remains with associated prints. Items date from 1945 to 2011 with the bulk of the collection dating between 1966 and 1999.
All negatives are identified with an identification number and, in most cases, an accompanying title. For instance, a negative sleeve reading 684.10 would translate to "April 1968, roll 10." Photographic prints also bear this identification with the addition of the frame number such as, "684.10-28." Most prints also bear a stamp with Martin's name and address.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of the National Day of Mourning march in Pittsburgh on April 7, 1968 are digitized and available online.
Negatives (Photographic); Photographs; Photographers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Business and Industry; Associations; Historic sites -- Pennsylvania, Western; Civil rights demonstrations -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Allegheny County (Pa.); Pittsburgh (Pa.); Bradford Woods (Pa.); Ocracoke Island (N.C.); Gelatin silver prints; Visiting Nurse Association of Allegheny County (Pa.); Ford, Gerald R.; Scranton, William Warren; Pittsburgh Blind Association; Randall, Tony; Bleier, Rocky; Kellogg Media Group; Kmart Corporation; American Red Cross; University Club (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Shady Side Academy (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Richard King Mellon Foundation; Carlow College (Oakland, Pittsburgh, Pa.); Vibra-Tech Engineers; Martin family; Hill House (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Goodwill of Southwestern Pennsylvania; Goodwill Industries of Pittsburgh; Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children; United Way of Allegheny County (Pa.); King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968 -- Assassination; St. Barnabas Foundation; Cross Electronics Inc; Salvation Army; Boy Scouts of America
- Pittsburgh March on the National Day of Mourning for MLK, Jr., April 7, 1968; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains 189 35mm black and white negatives taken by Martin on April 7, 1968 that document the march that occurred in Pittsburgh on the National Day of Mourning three days after the assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. on April 4, 1968. The images in this series are scanned and appear online. Never published before, these images provide the most significant and unique documentation of the march.
  - 35mm Negatives, April 7, 1968 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Prints, April 7, 1968 (Box 81, Folder 2)
- Negatives, 1945-1998; II.
  This series contains negatives taken by Martin dating from 1946 to 1998 and document his travels, client work, personal, and experimental photography. Topics include the Republic of China, Visiting Nurses Association, Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, Hill House, Boy Scouts of America, Chatham College, Pittsburgh, Ocracoke Island, United Fund, and Dynamic Equipment, among others.
  - 35mm Negatives, 1.
    - 1946
      - Republic of China, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
    - ca. 1950
      - Misc. Family 1950's, ca. 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Bob Schmerz Architect, Composer, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Personal, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - 1964
      - Kitty – Mac – Tom – Ermie, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Tom on Tricycle, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1965
      - Mac & Tom playing, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1966
      Subjects include Chatham College; Point Park College; Hutchinson; Mellon Bank; and the Boy Scouts of America-Camp Semiconon; unidentified images. Also included are Martin's personal photographs. There are also camera and film test images of various buildings such as the AT&T Employees Federal Credit Union, the U.S. Steel Tower, and the First Lutheran Church.
      - Marionettes and Portraits, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Portraits and Event, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Portraits, School, and Cars, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Children, Cats, and the Outdoors, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Portraits, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 19-20, 63)
      - Dog, House, Agreement of Sale, and Statue, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Spray Painting/ Painting, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22-25)
      - Music, Lamp Post, Kids, and Painting, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Ridge Avenue Christian Church, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Visiting Nurses Association, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 28-33)
      - Fisk University, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 34-54)
      - Kuhlber, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 55-57)
      - Hill House, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 58-62)
      - Flat Ironing Hair and the Outdoors, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 64)
      - Portraits, Business Cards, Nature and Photo Gallery, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
        Business card prints are also included.
      - Hill House Kids, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3, 5-7, 9-11)
      - Portraits and Cooking, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - T.V. or Not T.V., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Outdoor Group Activity, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Dogs, Cars, and Nature, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Kids Portraits and the Outdoors, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - City Shots and Candid People Shots, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Kids Playing, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Mellon Bank, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18-20)
      - United Fund, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 21-30)
      - Car Dealership, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Personal, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
      - Nature and Construction, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Boy Scouts of America, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 35-40)
      - Boy Scouts of America, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1-11)
      - Kids and Outdoors, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - City and Cars, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Lectures, Animals, and Kids, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Fighting Bulls - Spain, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 15-17)
      - Mellon Bank, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 18-23)
      - Various Buildings- Nikon 28, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 24-25, 28)
      - Various Buildings– Canon 19, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
      - Personal, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Chatham College, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 30-40)
      - Chatham College, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1-7, 10-13, 19-20, 21-29)
      - Marionettes and Copies of Grades, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Sam Law, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Brown Children, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 14-18)
      - Point Park, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 30-41)
      - Personal, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 42-44)
      - Hutchinson, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 45-49)
      - Portraits- Porteus, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Point Park, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1-10)
      - Personal, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 11-13)
    - 1967
      Subjects include the United Fund; Christmas Cards; Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children; Point State Park; Gilbert Lumber; U.S.S. Crucible Steel Plant; Okracoke Island, North Carolina; Hazelwood Christian Church (HCC); Bert Hollerran- Building; United Way; Volkswagen; and Forman, Dorsey, Bashford & Wallace. Also included are Martin's personal photographs.
      - Point Park, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 14-15, 18-21, 31-41)
      - Volkswagen, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 23-26)
      - Personal, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 22, 42-46, 48-49)
      - United States Steel, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 27-30)
      - C.I.D.C, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 50)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1-7, 10-14, 16-18, 24-30, 45, 48-58)
      - Gilbert Lumber (Luke), 1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Personal, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9, 31, 38, 47, 59-61)
      - United Fund, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 21-23, 32-37)
      - Bashford- Haines School, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Crucible Steel, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 39-42)
      - Bert Holleran, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 43-44)
      - Pressley House, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - Personal, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 1-2, 4, 8, 43-44)
      - Okracoke, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 5-7, 12-13)
      - Bert Holleran, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 9-11, 14-16)
      - Point Park, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 17-36)
      - Personal- Sailboat, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Hazelwood Christian Church, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 38-42, 48-50)
      - Foreman Dorsch Bashford & Wallace, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 45-46)
      - D-76 Test, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 47)
      - Alcoa, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 48)
      - Hazelwood Christian Church, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 1-21)
      - Foreman Dorsch Bashford & Wallace, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 22, 34-35, 37)
      - Personal, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 23, 33, 36)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 24-32)
      - United Fund, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 38-39)
    - 1968
      Subjects include the Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children; Boys Club; the United Fund; Forman, Dorsey, Bashford & Wallace; Goodwill; McBeth-Geyser; Bradford Woods Community Church; Hazelwood Christian Church (HCC). Also included are Martin's personal photos and camera test photos.
      - Foreman Dorsch Bashford & Wallace, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Leica / Nikon Camera Tests, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 2-3, 11, 21)
      - Roth, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 4-10)
      - United Fund- Vocational Rehabilitation, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 11-18)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 23-26, 38, 43-49)
      - United Fund- Louise Childcare, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 32-37)
      - Visiting Nurses Association, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 39-42)
      - Personal & Sewickley "Y", 1968 (Box 9, Folder 50)
      - MTI Television, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 51)
      - Chatham College, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 52-53)
      - United Fund- Goodwill, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 54-55)
      - United Fund- Goodwill, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
      - Visiting Nurses Association, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
      - Pressley House, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 8-16)
      - Personal, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 17, 26-28)
      - United Fund- Boys Club, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 18-25)
      - United Fund- Holy Family Institution, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 29-35)
      - Gail Fithian- Passport Pictures, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 36)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 37-39)
      - United Fund- President Club Meeting, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 40-43)
      - Bradford Woods Couples Club, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 44-49)
      - United Fund- Board Meeting, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 50)
      - United Fund- Board Meeting, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
      - Bradford Woods Community Church (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 4-16, 24-25, 33-34, 42-48)
      - Couples Club– Personal– Leica, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - United Fund, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 18-23)
      - Hazelwood Christian Church, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 26-30, 38-40)
      - Personal, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 31, 56)
      - Personal – Blade Nikkormat Focus, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Rafting, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 35, 37)
      - PA Well Drillers Association Meeting, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - VEE-JAYS, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 41)
      - Personal – Ocracoke, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 49)
      - Personal & Bud's House, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 50)
      - Bradford Woods Community Church, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 51)
      - Foreman Dorsch Bashford & Wallace, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 52-53)
      - D. Hadley, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 54)
      - Goodwill- Dining Halls, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 55)
      - J. Evans, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 57-58)
      - J. Evans, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 1-2, 54-55)
      - Foreman Dorsch Bashford & Wallace, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - United Fund– Roselia Hospital, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 4-8)
      - McBeth– Geyser Job, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 9-11)
      - Personal, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 12-15, 55)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 16-19, 23-27)
      - Personal– Point Park, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Bill Snyder, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - U.U. Church, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - United Fund, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children- Laura, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 39-43, 51-53)
      - MARC & Co. – ICM Job II, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 44-45)
      - United Fund– JHA, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 46-50)
      - Personal– Mom & Dad, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 54)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children – Xmas Party, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 56-58)
    - 1969
      Subjects include the Pittsburgh Racquet Club; the Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children; Goodwill; Booth Memorial Hospital; the United Fund; Market Square; Pressley Ridge; ICM School of Business; Hazelwood Christian Church (HCC). Also included are Martin's personal photographs.
      - Kranich and Associates AIA Pittsburgh Racquet Club, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 14-15)
      - United Fund- Speech & Hearing Inst. Xmas Party, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 1-3, 10-15, 20)
      - Personal, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 4,9,21, 28, 48-49)
      - United Fund– JHA, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 5-8)
      - Marc & Co.– ICM Job, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 16-10)
      - Personal– Schmartz Vows, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 22-25, 54-55)
      - Goodwill, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 26-27, 30-33)
      - Buhl Class, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 29)
      - ICM, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 34-37)
      - MARC– ICM Baltimore, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 38-44)
      - MARC- ICM PGH, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 45-47)
      - MARC– ICM, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 48-53)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 1-5, 13-17, 55-56)
      - Pressley House, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
      - Community Service of Pennsylvania, March 6, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
      - Buhl – Sex Ed., 1969 (Box 14, Folder 10-12)
      - Goodwill, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 18-19, 37, 43-44)
      - Vibra-Tech, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 20, 26)
      - Martin, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children - Airport, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 22-25, 27)
      - United Fund– Health O Rama, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 28-31)
      - Prinz Test, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 32)
      - United Fund– Girl Scouts, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 33-36)
      - Hazelwood Christian Church- Dedication, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 40)
      - Girls Track, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 38)
      - Schmartz, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 39)
      - United Fund– Girl Scouts, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 33-35, 41)
      - Goodwill– Melta Bland, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 42)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children– Court House, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 45-47)
      - Fallingwater, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 50)
      - Personal– John Ellis Portraits, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 51)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children– SCCA Rally, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 52-54)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
      - Pressley Ridge School, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - United Fund– Board Meeting, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 5-14)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 15-30, 52-55)
      - Cross Electronics & Mt. Lebanon Girls Track, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - VT Bell Telephone Building, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 32-33)
      - Personal & VT Bell Telephone Building, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 34)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children- 3 Rivers Art Festival, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 35-38)
      - 3 Rivers Festival, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 40)
      - Beckman, Swenson & Associates, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 41)
      - Personal– Dayton National AUU Track Meet, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 42-43)
      - Personal, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 44, 48-49)
      - Personal 35 Nikon Test, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 45)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children – Summer Play, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 51)
      - Estey Co. Zelie for Deerfield Co., 1969 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 1-10, 46-47, 51-53)
      - Pittsburgh and Quantico, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 11-12)
      - Unidentified Subjects, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - United Fund Copy of Red Cross Vietnam Picture, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - Goodwill Copies (for Prints or Slides), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - Goodwill Copies (Not Taken By Martin), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - United Fund- Neighborhood Center Association, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 20-22)
      - United Fund- Booth Memorial Hospital, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 23-24)
      - United Fund- Pittsburgh Child Guidance Center, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 25-26, 28)
      - United Fund- Booth Memorial Hospital/Pittsburgh Child Guidance Center, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 27)
      - United Fund- Rankin Christian Center, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 29-38)
      - United Fund- Miss Torch Girls, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 39-44)
      - Windwood Swim Club (Personal), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 45)
      - Market Square, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 50, 54)
      - Market Square, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 1-2, 8, 10)
      - United Fund- Det. Workers Allegheny Y, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
      - Buhl Field Trip, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 7, 20)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 9, 11-19, 22, 24)
      - Canon Summitar Test, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children- Thanksgiving (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Canon Summitar Test- Tom, Jayne, Colton, Kit (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - United Fund, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 26-30)
      - Xmas Cards/Business Cards, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - 1970
      Subjects include the Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children; United Fund; Goodwill; Cross Electronics; ICM School of Business; Vibra-Tech; Ruth Swenson, Pressley Ridge; Chatham College; Market Square; Kellogg Media Group. Also included are Martin's personal photographs.
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 33-41)
      - United Fund- Red Cross, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 42-45)
      - United Fund- Arthritis Foundation, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 46-48)
      - United Fund- Cerebral Palsy, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 49-54)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 1-7, 22-23, 37-40, 50)
      - Market Square- Winter, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Personal, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 9-10, 21, 24)
      - United Fund- Salvation Army, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 11-20)
      - Buhl Class, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 25)
      - Jean Farm, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 26)
      - Beckman, Swenson & Associates, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 27)
      - Personal- Snow Pix & & Xmas Cards, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 28)
      - Personal- Canon, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 29,31)
      - Market Square, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 30)
      - Eclipse & Buhl Field Trip, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 32)
      - Building- 7th & Smithfield, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 33)
      - Personal- Test, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 34)
      - Salvation Army, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 35-36)
      - PA. Association of Nursing Homes, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 41)
      - Kellogg Media Group- Seabreeze, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 42-49)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 1-5, 31-41, 49-57)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children- Tree Preservation, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Chatham College, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 7-8, 11-23, 42, 46-47)
      - Market Square, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 9, 44-45)
      - Buick S.W. Accident, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Community Service of Pennsylvania, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 24-30)
      - Salvation Army, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 43)
      - Personal, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 48)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 1, 12-14, 17, 19-25, 28)
      - Media Graphics, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Personal– H.S. Graduation, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Pressley Ridge Association, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
      - United Fund, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 6-11, 16, 26-27, 49)
      - Multi Media- Ear Mold, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children- 8th Grade Picture, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Personal- Canon 35, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 29)
      - Media Graphics- Easy Method, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 30-31)
      - Personal- 35 mm Nikon, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 32)
      - ICM (Box 20, Folder 33)
      - Personal- Vacation, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 34)